我一直努力想无视我的感受  但我做不到
All I want to do is stop feeling
what I'm feeling, but I can't,
前情提要
我不知道该如何是好
and I.. do not know what to do any more.
幕雨字幕组译制
我只想留在你身旁  仅此而已
I just want to be near you,nothing more.
翻译：Brynt&超威闫叔  校对：Brynt&超威闫叔
这里发生的一切都与爱情无关  知道吗
What happens here has got nothing to do with love, all right?
时间轴：花格子神尼&拜仁小攀  后期：Brynt
从哪回来的就回哪儿去  之前做什么就继续做去
Go back to wherever it is you go.
Keep doing whatever you're doing.
我爱你  但是我不能再继续没有爱的生活
I love you but I can't live without...love.
情况严重吗
It's that serious?
做个活细胞组织检查  我就能了解更多
The tests, the biopsy,should tell me more.
我并不想伤害你
I don't want to hurt you.
给我你的陈词跟照片
Let me have the statements and the photographs.
- 但我要是给了你的话我就会失去你  - 求你了
- But I'll lose you if I give them to you.- Please!
这就是正在将年轻的波尔赛弗捏拉进
So, here we have Hades seizing the beautiful young Persephone,
死亡的国度-冥府的哈迪斯
dragging her down to the realm of the dead.
或许你们有人早已对以描绘蹂躏
Some of you may be familiar with the celebrated Bernini sculpture,
而享誉世界的雕塑家贝尔尼尼非常熟悉
which depicts the same rape,
尽管他比你们早生了八十年
although it predates this by some 80 years.
- 抱歉  - 不不  没关系的
- Sorry. - No, no, it's fine.
现在才开始呢
It's only just begun.
希望我不会被训斥
Hope I don't get told off.
真好玩啊
What fun!
我们也不能对残暴的老哈迪斯过于苛刻
We mustn't be too harsh on fierce old Hades.
毕竟他还是让她做了个可靠的女人
After all, he did make an honest woman of her.
她最后成为了冥后
She became Queen of the Underworld.
- 我来帮您提包  - 不不  不劳烦了
- Can I get your bags? - No, no, no.
- 我可不像看起来那样弱不禁风  - 那再见了  夫人
- I'm stronger than I look. - Ma'am.
在这边  鲍威尔先生
In here, Mr Powell.
你打算什么时候给我做手术
So...when do you cut me open?
明天一早
First thing tomorrow.
非常好
Splendid.
屏息
第一季第五集
这个大鸟笼是由一位不知名的建筑家设计的
The aviary, which was designed by an unknown architect,
一直到一九八九年才竣工
was finally completed in 1889.
是因为太热了才不能赶工的
Far too hot to hurry.
当巴伦住在这里时  经常到这里来喂鸟儿食
Whenever the Baron was in residence,
he used to come here to feed the birds.
据说这里的鸟儿都已经认得出他的声音了呢
We're told the birds actually recognised his voice.
我们先进去歇会儿吧
We'll just step in here.
鲍威尔夫人
Mrs Powell.
真是意外之喜啊
What a surprise.
穆里根先生
Mr Mulligan.
我是安德伯雷太太
Mrs Enderbury.
安德伯雷太太  哦~
Mrs Enderbury? Oh.
真迷人
Enchanted.
真是太巧了  对吧
Marvellous, isn't it?
你觉得鸟儿快乐吗
Do you think the birds are happy?
我觉得它们很快乐  你看它们不是都在歌唱吗
I'd say they are. They're singing, anyway.
你对园艺感兴趣吗  穆里根先生
Are you interested in gardening,Mr Mulligan?
真是多此一问
Silly question.
你肯定对园艺很感兴趣  不然你也不会到这儿来了
You must be, or you wouldn't be here.
哦~  我们得走了
Oh, hold on tight, we're moving.
你先去吧  莉莉  我有些私事要跟穆里根先生聊
You go ahead, Lily. I just want a private word with Mr Mulligan.
你跑这里来干嘛
What are you doing here?
我们现在情况很不利
We got off on the wrong foot.
你答应要把文件给我的
You promised me the files.
你逼我跟你...做那种事
You forced me to let you...do what you did.
然后你就会闭口不言
And then didn't keep your word.
- 我并不引以为傲  - 谎言还是淫行
- I'm not proud of that. - The lie or the rape?
不要这样  不是那样的  别那样叫  求你了
Please.It wasn't that,don't call it that.Please.
我来这儿是想问你...
I'm here to ask you...
是想乞求你把那件事抛诸脑后
to beg you, to put all that behind us.
这样我们就能够重新开始
So we can start again.
根本就没有什么文件
There are no files.
你什么把柄都没有
You had nothing.
非常荣幸能认识你的朋友
Very pleased to meet your friend.
查尔斯・安德伯雷太太
Mrs Charles Enderbury.
你丈夫的共犯
Your husband's accomplice?
他好像人...还挺友善的...
He seemed um...very nice...
你的那个神秘先生
your mysterious man.
住口
Shut up.
抱歉
Sorry.
莉莉  这非常重要  你绝对不可以向任何人提到他
Lily, please, really, it's so important. You mustn't mention him to anyone.
- 即使是奥托跟查理  - 好吧
- Not Otto, not Charlie. - All right.
尤其是查理  你能答应我吗
Especially not Charlie. Do you promise?
很好
Good.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们不能再谈这件事
We need never refer to it again.
好了
Right.
我们得跟上观光团了
Better catch up with the tour.
- 今天真闷啊  - 对啊  谁说不是呢
- Stifling today. - Yes, isn't it?
我现在恨不得吃一大块冰块
I'd kill for an ice.
你现在可没时间穿比基尼
You'll be wearing a bikini in no time.
- 好了  各位  我们走吧  - 特拉斯科特医生
- Right,chaps,on we go. - Dr Truscott?
能小聊两句吗
Quick word?
休息一会儿  各位
Stand easy, chaps.
我觉得该告知你一声  玛格丽特・道尔顿在私人病房
Thought I should let you know. Margaret Dalton's here, in a private room.
什么
What?
玛格丽特上周过来找我
Margaret came to see me last week.
说她腹部阵痛  食欲不振
Abdominal pain, loss of appetite...
房事之后还出血
some bleeding after sex.
你不想知道这事儿吗
You weren't aware of that?
你给她检查过了吗
You examined her?
送过样本给实验室了
And sent a smear to the lab.
她患上了宫颈癌
She has cervical cancer.
很抱歉告诉你这个坏消息
Sorry to be the bearer of bad news.
不  别开玩笑了  我跟她不怎么熟
No, don't be ridiculous. I barely know her.
我明天就给她做手术
I'm operating tomorrow.
好吧  要只是宫颈的问题  倾刻间就能解决
Right, well, if it's just the cervix, we can whip it out in a trice.
要是扩散了的话  摘除子宫就行了
If it's spread, hysterectomy.
嗯  到时候再说吧
Yes, we'll see.
介意让我一个人坐电梯上去吗
Mind if I come along for the ride?
- 不介意  - 很好
- Not at all. - Excellent.
- 很高兴在这儿遇到你  - 嗯
- Fancy meeting you here. - Yes.
毕竟我是这个医院的医生嘛
A doctor in a hospital.
真诡异
Bizarre.
我上周给你公寓那边打过几通电话
I phoned you last week a couple of
times, called round at the flat...
我一直在避免接触他人
I've been rather incommunicado.
不好意思
Sorry.
不用道歉
No.
我理解
No, understood.
那...
So, er...
- 鲍威尔对你治疗得还好吗  - 当然
- Powell been treating you all right? - Mm.
那个自负的混蛋
Conceited bastard.
自以为是伦敦地区最好的妇科医生
Thinks he's the best gynae surgeon in London.
但是我告诉你个小秘密
But I'll let you into a little secret.
他确实是
He is.
那我不是很幸运地会安然无恙吗
Well,aren't I the lucky one,landing on my feet?
梅塔明天会替我  我明天那时候有个约会
Mehta will cover for me tomorrow,I've got an appointment.
知道了
Fine.
好吧  其实我是要去找份别的工作
Yes. No, it's about another job.
是在圣奥尔本医院一个部门主管职位
At St Albans - head of department.
- 哦  太好了  - 对
- Oh, terrific. - Yes.
很抱歉如此唐突地告诉你
Sorry to spring it on you.
他们上周打过电话过来
They got in touch last week...
说想要我推荐个人过去
wanted a reference.
- 你怎么都没跟我提  - 你也没先跟我提这事儿啊
- You didn't mention it. - You didn't mention it.
我是没有
No.
我担心会让你陷入尴尬的境地
I'm worried about leaving you in the lurch.
不必担心  老兄  我早已另有人选了
No,don't,old chap.I can always get someone else.
- 那我们揽的私活呢  - 也有人选了
- What about the Specials? - Yes, those too.
说实在的  查理
Honestly, Charlie.
这是你的生活  你的事业  去吧
It's your life, your career. Please.
去追求你的理想
Pursue it.
现在你快去吧
Now buzz off.
谢了  老兄
Thanks, old man.
对了
Oh...
祝你超好运
Best of bloody luck.
奥利弗的父亲是怎么死的
How did Oliver's father die?
我不记得书里怎么讲的了
I don't remember in the book.
可能是他们来让我们去看演出了
They may tell us in the show.
- 夫人  - 谢谢
- Madam. - Oh, thank you.
给鲍威尔夫人  维布鲁克大街  圣玛格丽特（检察长送）
明天下午三点  里士满  蓝普顿船坞
好漂亮的花
They're beautiful!
- 要我把它们插起来吗  - 扔掉
- Shall I put them in water? - Throw them away.
拜托了
Please.
我可不想成为孤儿
I shouldn't like to be an orphan.
你不会成孤儿的
Well, you won't be one.
我们要见爸爸的话你就得快点了
We'll need to hurry if we're meeting Daddy.
护士  走之前你能帮我把贝克夫人的笔记拿过来一下吗
Before you go,Nurse,could you fetch
Mrs Baker's notes?
护士
Nurse?
Nurse!
我...
I...
我一直在想
I've been thinking.
我们应该...
We should...
我们确实应该
We should.
谈谈  或是...
..just talk or...
我们先出去吧
Let's get out of here.
谢谢惠顾  夫人
Thank you, ma'am.
- 老爸  - 伊丽莎白
- Daddy! - Elizabeth.
这是威尔森护士  这位是我夫人
This is Nurse Wilson, Mrs Powell.
以及犬子  托马斯
And our son, Thomas.
很荣幸认识你
Pleased to meet you.
- 我也是  - 我们要去手术室看奥利弗
-Likewise.-We're going to see Oliver at the theatre
- 希望你能喜欢  - 谢谢
- Hope you enjoy it. - Thank you.
你兴奋吗
Are you excited?
我也是
Me too.
你要起床了吗
Are you getting up?
抱歉
Sorry.
我睡不着
Can't sleep.
我也睡不着
Me neither.
出什么事儿了吗
What's the problem?
没事儿
Nothing.
什么事儿也没有
Nothing, nothing at all.
不想扫了你的兴
Don't want to bore you with it.
谁啊
Who's that?
是我  老爸
It's me, Dad.
你好  简
Hello, Jean.
我刚起床正在房间里看书呢
Just been up reading in my bedroom.
- 你继续看吧  小莫  - 吉妮
- You just carry on, Mo. - Jeannie.
你怎么跟个笨蛋似的站在那儿
What are you standing there for,like a lemon?
过来坐会儿吧
Come and sit down.
- 我才不是笨蛋呢  - 先坐下再说
- I'm not a lemon. - Sit yourself down.
你妹妹还在医院上班呢
Your sister's at work at the hospital.
你今天气色不错  老爸
You seem well today, Dad.
我身体一直都好得很呢
I'm always well.
一直都是
Always well.
你呢
And you?
当然也很好
Yeah. I'm fine.
喝茶吗
Cup of tea?
你有没有...
Did you ever...
爱过除妈妈之外的
love anyone else...
其他人
..apart from Mum?
没有
No.
我只爱过她一人
Always her.
从我们第一支舞开始就只爱着她
From the first dance.
你真幸运
You were lucky.
她也是
And so was she.
你也会同样幸运的
And you will be too.
别担心了
Don't you worry.
我陪你到走廊走走
I'll walk you down the aisle.
你不介意我去对吧  我不想束缚到你的发挥
You don't mind me coming, do you?
I don't want to cramp your style.
你看起来...简直是太美了
You look...terrific.
查理  邻居们都看着呢
Charlie, the neighbours!
- 去他的邻居们  - 查理（娇笑中）
- Damn the neighbours. - Charlie! (GIGGLES)
感觉我们就是在冒险一样
It's like we're on an adventure.
不好意思  你现在不能饮食
Sorry, you can't eat or drink.
带火了吗
Got a light?
终于看到你的另一面了
See you on the other side.
老朋友了
Old friends.
奥托：准备开第一刀
OTTO: First incision.
- 梅塔医生  - 请继续吧
- Dr Mehta? - Please proceed.
我会代替安德伯雷医生在旁边协助你的
I am a cumbersome stand-in for Dr Enderbury.
没别的意思
Not at all.
他是个可靠的副手
A trusty lieutenant.
我觉得你跟他都无需多言  点个头眨下眼他就明白了
I imagine you barely need to speak, just a nod and a wink.
- 我俩亲密无间  - 确实
- Thick as thieves. - Indeed.
你们是在哪儿认识的
And where was your alliance forged?
陆军医务队  你介意我们能先不聊天吗
Army Medical Corps. Do you mind awfully if we don't chat?
一点也不
Not at all.
我也不想干扰到你
I wouldn't want to unsettle you.
- 不是吗  - 当然
- No? - Of course not.
我不说了
Perish the thought.
安德伯雷先生
Dr Enderbury?
我是沃尔顿  欢迎
Watson. Welcome.
荣幸之至
Pleasure.
计划有点小变动  索姆斯先生现在
Slight change of plan,Mr Soames is tied up in
正在做一场紧急外科手术  那可是疑难杂症
emergency surgery - unexpected complications.
啊  老难杂了
Ah, the old UC.
- 就是“疑难杂症”  - 哦  我知道
- Unexpected complications. - Ah, yes.
那我先带你逛逛这儿吧
So, let me give you  a tour of the ship,
你吃完午饭之后
and after you've had a break for lunch,
我们两点钟再在这儿见面如何
could we reconvene here at two?
没问题
Fine.
谢谢
Thank you.
索姆斯先生迫不及待的想见到你呢
Mr Soames is eager to meet you.
我们已经很久没见过如此热情的推荐函了
We've seldom seen such glowing references.
不敢相信你你所听到的了吗
Can't believe everything you hear?
他们说你非常谦虚
They said you were modest.
也没那么谦虚啦
Not that modest.
我们先四处看看吧
Let's go and look at it.
癌细胞已经扩散到骨盆跟腺体
Carcinoma widespread -pelvis, glands.
天呐
Jesus Christ.
我们可以摘除卵巢  宫颈跟子宫
We can take out the ovaries,the cervix and uterus.
但是癌细胞扩散太快  已经没办法阻止了
But the cancer's rampant.We can't cut it all out.
我们必...必须得试试
We have... We have to try.
不行  我们不能这样做
No, we don't.
因为  我再重申一遍  已经回天乏术了
Because, I repeat, it's not possible.
要是你不做的话  我来
If you won't, I will.
- 你再说一遍  - 要是我不试试的话她会死的
- I beg your pardon? - She'll die if I don't.
你要是这样做的话她立马会死
She'll die now if you do.
她是我的病人  特拉斯科特先生
She's my patient, Mr Truscott.
我不能让你杀了她
I can't allow you to kill her.
天气真好啊
Lovely day.
她待会儿就会恢复神智
She'll be conscious in a minute.
必须有人得告诉她这个噩耗
Someone has to tell her.
我不确定是否能胜任这项任务
Not sure I'm up to that.
你绝对可以
You are.
而且你也会去的
You will be.
感觉如何
How are you feeling?
头昏脑胀的
Bit woozy.
杜松子酒喝多了吧
Too many G&Ts.
一切都还顺利吗
So, everything OK?
我们已经...
There's noth...
我们已经无能为力了
There's nothing we can do.
你六个月之前肯定就已经知道了
You must have known six months ago,
some pain...which you ignored,
但是因为你很坚强  那么...完美无瑕
because you're so...independent,so...
所以你才忽略了那些疼痛
..so flawless.
我本应该注意到的 我本应该看出来的  但我没...
I should have noticed,I should have seen but I could...
而我没有  因为我从来都没想到你会出什么事
..I couldn't,because I could never imagine anything wrong with you.
对此我深表感激
I'm very grateful for that.
你就别再自责了
Please don't blame yourself.
到这来
Come here.
到我这儿来
快来
Come.
【叹息】
(SIGHS)
我还有多少时日  几个月
How long have I got? Months?
几周
Weeks?
或许吧
Maybe.
猜猜是谁
Guess who?
查理
Charlie!
外科医生还在手术室呢
The surgeon was in theatre.
一小时之后才会回去
Got to be back in an hour.
这个小镇太美了  查理
It's such a lovely town, Charlie.
我看到有做很不错的房子在出售
I saw a darling little house for sale.
就等着我们去住呢
It's all there for the taking.
那我们这一小时能做点什么呢
So, what can we do with an hour?
天呐
Gosh!
史...密...斯
S-M-I-T-H.
没有行李
No luggage.
走吧  史密斯太太  我们时间不多哦
Come on, Mrs Smith, we haven't got all day.
这艘船还不错  对吧  还能在敦克尔克接活儿呢
Not a bad little boat, is she? Could've done a job at Dunkirk.
你就让我来看这个
Is this what you've brought me to see?
我这些天来就是把那些东西藏这儿的
This is where I've kept them in recent weeks.
什么东西
Kept what?
那些文件
The files.
看一下吧
Take a peek.
你知道这些事谁的  对吧
You know whose it is, don't you?
还有我发现它的地方
And where I found it.
那个死去的男人血迹斑斑的鞋
The dead man's blood-stained shoe.
这些证据就足以使鲍威尔跟安德伯雷俩人都锒铛入狱
Proof, if proof were needed, to convict both Powell and Enderbury.
不  你留着吧  请自便
No, keep it, feel free.
好时刻都提醒着你
A reminder.
这儿还有很多照片跟陈词之类的
There's more here-photos,statements,et cetera.
你见不到这艘船对她来说最好
You're not seeing her at her best.
我们过去一直都让她停在这小河上并保持着整洁
We used to keep her spick and span.
斯图尔特他会帮我打理着这船
He'd help me, Stewart would.
我的儿子
My son.
他当时多大
How old was he?
九岁
Nine.
他总借着水闸的水在河上飘荡
He was upriver in this boat in a lock.
他喜欢水闸...
He liked the locks...
水流倾泻而出  而我们就在水面上漂流
water pouring in,lifting us slowly up.
我妻子跟女儿总在我跟水闸看守员聊天时在小屋里做些三明治
My wife and daughter were in the cabin making
sandwiches, I was chatting to the lock-keeper.
我听见斯图尔特开怀大笑着
I heard Stewart laughing.
他不停地喊着：“爸爸  爸爸”
He called, 'Dad, Dad!'
我以为他看到什么东西了
I thought he must've seen something.
但你绝对不会去打扰你的父亲
But you don't interrupt your father.
你绝对不会在他跟别人聊天时打断他的
You don't interrupt your father when he's talking, do you?
对吧
Do you?
不能哭  罗纳尔德  不能哭
Stop it, Ronald, stop it.
我没听见他进河里去了
I didn't hear him go in.
- 他溺水了吗  - 他溺水了
- He drowned? - He drowned.
我们让水排出了闸门之后才发现他
We let the water out of the lock and found him.
上一秒还开怀大笑着...
One moment you're laughing...
下一秒这个人却没了
the next you disappear.
我的心自此之后就停止了跳动
And my heart stopped...
直到我再次遇到了你
..until I saw you again.
再次
Again?
我还没告诉你我第一次见你的时候
I haven't told you about the first time.
那天天气热得很  塞浦路斯的阳光炙烤着大地
It was a baking day,the Cypriot sun beating down.
我走进那所黑色庄严的修道院医院
I came into the cool dark of a convent hospital.
走进一个像礼堂一样没有任何家具的房间
A bare room...like a chapel.
阳光从高高的窗户中射进来
Light from a high window.
还有一张床
And a bed.
在那张床上  躺着一个昏迷的女人
And in that bed, a woman lay, unconscious.
我看着她...
I looked at her...
几乎无法呼吸
..and I could hardly breathe.
就仿佛当时的阳光就是为她而闪耀
It was as if the light,somehow,was shining from her.
那是我此生见过最美的场景
You were the most beautiful sight I'd ever seen.
你现在依然还是
You still are.
你应该想想你的妻子
You should think about your wife...
你的女儿
your daughter.
不
No.
我只想要你
I just want you.
你跟托马斯
You and Thomas.
你不能拥有托马斯
You can't have Thomas!
你或许可以拥有我  但是你绝不能拥有托马斯
You may have had me but you can never have Thomas.
绝对不行
Never.
我不想用这个的  伊丽莎白
I don't want to use it, Elizabeth.
那就信守点承诺  别用那个  检察长
Then restore some honour,Inspector,and don't.
你愿意屈尊跟我周五一起去看《甜蜜的生活》吗
Would you deign to come and see La Dolce Vita, Friday?
（《甜蜜的生活》1960年意大利电影）
- 从没听过  - 其他电影也行  随便你选
- Never heard of it.- Or another film, any film.
呃...
Erm...
- 我会屈尊前往的  - 谢谢
- I'll deign to. - Thank you.
天呐  我终于又开始有心跳了
God, my heart's started beating again.
科恩  貌似你把你的学伴给弄丢了
Cohen,you seem to have lost your fellow students.
是的  鲍威尔先生  我马上去加入他们
Yes, Mr Powell, just rejoining them now.
昨天的事儿我很抱歉
I'm sorry about yesterday.
- 我感觉糟透了  - 我也是
- I...I felt awful. - So did I.
- 时机不对  - 时机不对
- Bad timing. - Bad timing.
- 奥托  - 有工作给你
- Otto? - Job for you.
私诊病人  上白班  这是她的地址
Private patient.Day shift.Here's her address.
谁跟你说我想要工作了
And who said I wanted a job?
她因为宫颈癌快要去世了  急需一个护士护理
She's dying.Cervical cancer.Needs a nurse.
- 我是个家庭主妇  - 不 你不是
- I'm a housewife. - No, you're not.
晚安
Good night.
我们走了的话肯定会很想你的  但你一定得过来看我们
Of course we'll miss you when we're gone but you must come and see us.
还有大教堂  我跟你说过大教堂吗
And the cathedral.Did I say there was a cathedral?
两只交叉
Oh. Well, fingers crossed.
去一个没人认识的新地方肯定非常棒
Mm.Must be so nice to go somewhere new where nobody knows you.
就带着托马斯一个人重新开始
Just take Thomas and start afresh.
还有奥托呢
And Otto.
对  当然了  托马斯需要他的父亲
Yes, of course.Thomas needs a father.
我没有跟查理或是任何人提...你的那个朋友
I didn't mention the er... you know,
your friend to Charlie or anyone.
很好
Good.
北一区  我是内维尔修女
North Wing One.Sister Neville speaking.
请稍等
Hold one moment.
护士  你的电话
Nurse? Telephone.
喂  我打给了简  但是她不在
Hello?I phoned Jean but she's not there.
他跑出去了  我把他弄不回来
He ran out of the house and I can't get him back.
好吧  小莫
All right, Mo.
他现在在公园里
He's in the park.
我马上就来
I'm coming.
你好意思  修女  我得回家一趟
Sorry,Sister,I need to go home.
出什么事啦吗
What's the problem?
- 煤气泄漏  - 煤气
- Gas leak. - Gas?
你不会对我撒谎的  对吧  小姐
You wouldn't be lying to me,would you,young lady?
- 去吧  去忙你的事儿吧   - 谢谢
- Go on.Do what you have to do. - Thank you.
- 我去坐公车  - 但我的车更快
- I'm getting the bus. - My car will be quicker.
但你会卷进来的
But you'll be in it.
那我只开车不说话  如何
Well, how about I don't talk? I'll just drive.
你好  我过来接管这边
Hello. I've come to take over.
啊~  简
Ah...Jean?
你就是...病人吗
Are you...the patient?
不好意思  鲍威尔先生没告诉我你的名字
Sorry, Mr Powell didn't tell me your name.
不是  我只是她的一个老朋友
No, I'm her oldest friend.
进去吧  她在等你
Go through, she's expecting you.
我一定看起来很可怕
I must look a fright.
我们之前见过面  对吧
We've met before, haven't we?
你是玛格丽特・道尔顿
You're Margaret Dalton.
- 你认识理查德  - 没错
- You know Richard. - I do.
看看你
Look at you.
你真是个可人儿
You're a peach.
- 离我远点儿  - 求你了  米切尔先生
- Get away from me! - Please, Mr Meecher.
- 我会淹死你的  你想被淹吗  - 求你了
- I'll drown you. You want drowning? - Please.
我只是想帮忙而已
I'm just trying to help you.
我过去可是在海峡游过泳  一天两次呢
I swam the Channel, I did. Twice a bloody day.
- 天呐  - 别管我
- Oh, God. - Leave me alone!
- 出去  - 米切尔先生
- Get out of it! - Mr Meecher!
你能...快出去
Can't you just... Get out of it!
- 小莫  - 我真的很抱歉
- Mo? - Oh, I'm so sorry.
快走吧  我就想一个人玩玩而已
Go on. I'm just trying to enjoy myself.
没事的  小莫  不是你的错
It's all right,Mo, not your fault.
爸  快出来
Dad! Get out of it!
爸
Dad!
快出来  里边不安全
Come out, it's not safe!
- 我还没玩够呢  - 求你了
- I'm not ready. - Please!
还没玩够  没玩够呢
Not ready, not ready!
给  帮我拿一下  好吗
Here. Hold this for me, will you?
你好  我想跟你一块玩
Hello. I thought I'd join you.
希望你别介意
Hope you don't mind?
我是你女儿的朋友
I'm a friend of your daughter's.
这样确实很好玩  也很酷
It's nice and cool.
没关系的
It's OK.
- 你的地址  - 嗯... 德雷克街五号
- What's his address? - Um...7 Drake Way.
你的名字
And your name is?
穆里根  莫林
Mulligan. Maureen.
- 手给我  爸  - 小心点
- Here you go, Dad. - Careful.
你在干嘛呢
What are you doing?
你可能想毒死我呢
You might want to poison me.
要不是我已经中毒够深了的话
If I wasn't already poisoned.
你需要打吗啡
You need morphia.
我觉得我现在需要一些吗啡
I think I will have some of that morphine now.
谢谢
Thank you.
我母亲也得过宫颈癌
My mother had cervical cancer.
六年前去世了
Died six years ago.
- 我很遗憾  - 我在家护理的他
- I'm sorry. - I nursed her at home.
我一直在努力...提升自我
I've tried to...improve myself.
变得端庄迷人
To be alluring and demure.
有能力  又不过分有能力  有好奇心  又风趣
Capable, not-too-capable, interested, amusing...
不让...我的家庭背景给我造成负担
Not...weighed down by my background.
我一直试着让他觉得我很完美
I've tried to be perfect for him.
你是怎么做到的
How do you do it?
不要再装作别人
Stop pretending to be somebody else.
你希望他爱你吗
You want him to love you?
去爱原原本本的你吗
To love you?
让他看到真实的你  做回自己
Well, let him see you. Be yourself.
真的  我以为门锁好了的
Really, I thought the door was locked.
没关系的  小莫
It's all right, Mo.
照顾他不是你一个人的责任  是我们共同的责任
He can't be your responsibility. He's ours.
很高兴见到你  先生
It was very nice to meet you, sir.
我再也不会让他跑出去了
I'll never let him go again.
- 你想娶我女儿吗  - 不是  爸  他...
- You looking for a wife? - No, Dad, he's...
他不是的
He's not.
你应该见过她的姐姐...简了
You should meet her sister - Jean.
我很乐意告诉你我已经有那个荣幸见过她了
I'm glad to say that I've already had that pleasure.
你是个幸运的男人
You're a very lucky man...
能有两个这么优秀的女儿
to have two such exceptional daughters.
我母亲死了之后  简就一个人在这儿照顾了老爸五年
After Mum died...Jean stayed here and cared for Dad for five years.
她有权利拥有一个不一样的未来
She has a right to a different future.
还有一个不一样的过去
And a different past.
应该是失去双亲  而有个非神经错乱的父亲这一耻辱
In which she loses both parents and avoided
the shame of a father of unsound mind.
那就让她这样
So be it.
不管是她的秘密  还是你的  我都会替你们保守
Her secret - and your secret - is safe with me.
- 你不会告诉理查德吗  - 我不会透露给任何人的
- You won't tell Richard? - I won't tell anyone.
我该进屋去了
I should go back in.
你在这儿干嘛呢
What are you doing here?
显而易见  不是吗
Isn't it obvious?
进来吧
Come in.
她在卧室呢
She's in the bedroom.
你知道卧室在哪儿吧
You know where that is.
不知道吗  那就跟我来吧
No? Follow me.
他来了
He's here.
你好
Hello.
今晚护士会过来陪她一小时
The night nurse will be here in an hour or so.
那我现在先走了  你们俩单独呆会儿吧
So I'll go now.Leave you two together.
- 真是愚蠢至极  - 但这一切都是谁造成的呢
- This is madness. - And who's responsible for it?
- 奥托  - 不是他  是你
- Otto. - No. You.
还有我
And me.
但他怎么能这样做  把简派到这儿来
But how could he? Sending Jean here.
这样我们就能见到对方  坦诚相见
So we could see each other,really see each other.
我们三个人都是
All three of us.
我很欣慰  你也该感到欣慰
I'm glad. You should be glad too.
过来  握住我的手
Come on, take my hand.
求你了
Please.
我很欣赏你的妻子
I love your wife.
而她又那么爱你
And she loves you.
别失去她
Don't lose her.
圣奥尔本医院寄过来的的  我能替你打开吗
It's from St Albans.Shall I open it for you?
不用了  但还是谢谢你
No. Thank you.
但这是我的事
My responsibility.
天呐
Oh, dear.
恐怕是坏消息
Bad news, I'm afraid.
没有新的开始了
No new start.
哦
Oh.
好吧
Oh, well.
算了
Never mind.
待会儿见
See you later.
振作点
Chin up.
你这几天一直对我避而不见
You've been avoiding me these last few days.
- 她怎么样了  - 你是说简还是玛格丽特
- How is she? - Jean or Margaret?
玛格丽特
Margaret.
茶饭无思  日益衰弱
Eating nothing. Fading.
但我很确信她受到很好的关怀  不是吗
But she's well cared for, I trust?
你做得太过了
You've got some nerve.
你以为你是我们的上司就能对我们为所欲为了吗
You think we're all in your theatre
and you can do whatever you want with us.
看样子你是不想让她得到好的照顾咯
So you don't want the best for her?
- 没人比简更适合照顾她了  - 特拉斯科特医生
- There's no one better than Jean.- Dr Truscott?
你的妻子打电话找你  说是事态紧急
Your wife's on the telephone. It's urgent.
书包拿了吗
Got your satchel?
我想开车送你们
I thought I might drive you.
早上好  托马斯
Morning, Thomas.
野猫把你的舌头吃了吗
Has the cat got your tongue?
- 早上好  先生  - 你的好意我心领了
- Good morning, sir. - What a kind offer.
但我不想再给你添麻烦
I couldn't put you to so much trouble.
一点钟再过来如何
But, please, come back at, say, one?
一起吃个午餐
We'll have lunch.
乐意之至
Very good.
- 他是谁啊  - 一个老朋友
- Who was he? - An old friend.
我们家的老朋友
Of the family.
我们不能告诉爸爸这件事  不然会破坏这份惊喜的
Now we mustn't mention him to Daddy,
else it'll spoil the surprise.
要是男孩子能保守秘密就会有糖奖励哦
And there'll be special sweets for boys who can keep secrets.
我想感谢你那天为我父亲所做的事
I wanted to thank you... for what
you did the other day with my father.
不用  我很开...非常开心这么做
No, I was happy...more than happy.
我得问你一些问题
I need to ask you some questions.
关于你 关于你的婚姻
About you. About your marriage.
- 你讨厌你的妻子吗  - 不
-Are you going to tell me you hate your wife?-No
那她不理解你吗
But she doesn't understand you?
她理解我  非常理解
She understands me. Very well.
还是说...
But the...
- 浪漫  - 浪漫吗
..romance... - The romance?
- 已经不复存在了  - 不
- ..has died? - No.
我们从未有过浪漫
It was never there.
从来没有过
Ever.
我从来都没跟她亲热过
I have...never even kissed her.
- 但你有个儿子  - 对
- You have a son. - Yes.
- 我们是有个儿子  - 但这说不通啊
- We have a son. -It doesn't make sense.
会的
It will.
总有一天会说得通的  要是你肯信任我的话
One day it will.If...you can just trust me.
你对我还隐瞒了什么
What are you hiding?
- 我现在不能告诉你  - 那我们就不能再继续发展下去
-I can't tell you.-Then we can't go any further.
我们来了
We're close.
理查德来了
Richard's here.
玛格丽特
Margaret?
我让你们单独呆会儿吧
I'll leave you two alone.
不
No.
留下来吧
Stay.
留下来陪我
Please stay with me.
我没有得到
Didn't get it.
那份工作
The job.
抱歉了  老兄  你暂时摆脱不了我了
So, sorry, chum, you're stuck with me.
不  对我来说是件好事  我们是好搭档嘛
No, that's great for me. We're a good team.
没错  对吧
We are, aren't we?
自从塞浦路斯事件之后
Ever since Cyprus.
你在驾驶座上
You in the driving seat.
- 我们相互依靠  - 没错
- Depending on each other. - Absolutely.
双手沾满鲜血
Blood on our hands.
一切都还好吧  查理
Everything all right, Charlie?
一切都好  很好
Everything's fine. Tickety-boo.
我不好
No...
说实话  我感到绝望了
Felt a bit dead out there,to be honest.
心里面空荡荡的
Like there was nothing at stake.
- 可是这...  - 你也脱不了干系
- Whereas here... - You're involved.
没错
Exactly.
鲍威尔先生  有你的电话
Mr Powell, telephone call for you.
奥托  我要你马上回家  马上
Otto, I need you to come home now.
我就知道你背叛了我
I knew you'd betray me.
我就知道
I knew.
还说什么“一点钟再过来”
'Come back at one.'
我从你眼里什么都看出来了
I saw it in your eyes.
你还有什么可辩解的
What have you got to say for yourself?
你不能  你不能...
You can't. You can't...
你怎么能这样对我  我向你袒露了我的心声
How could you? I bare my soul to you!
- 而你却转过来投进他的怀抱  - 他是我丈夫
- And you turn to him. - He's my husband.
你觉得他能与我相抗衡吗
You think he can confront me:
能与我这个拥有一切  无所不用其极
the man who has everything, who can
还能在事后还能逃避制裁的人相抗衡吗
do anything, and get away with it?
不  他不能
No. No, he can't.
你也看见过证据了
You saw the evidence.
你向他提到了我的名字
You mention me, you breathe my name
那么他那璀璨的人生就要终结了
to him and his charmed life is over.
还有你的  甚至是托马斯的
And yours. And Thomas's.
我的爱就那么一文不值吗
Does my love mean nothing?
- 殡仪承办方来了  - 谢谢
- The undertakers are coming. - Thank you.
出什么事了
What's wrong?
你从来都不关心家里
You're never here.
等等  这不完全是真的
Well, hang on, that's not entirely true.
确实是  即使你在关心这个家  也不是真在关心
It is. Even if you are,you're not really.
我当然关心这个家
Of course I am.
但不是你想关心的  也不是发自真心
Not in your head.Not in your...heart.
你陷入爱河了
You're falling in love.
但你不能  你知道规则的
Well, you can't. You know the rules.
你是他的父亲
You're his father.
我是他的父亲
I'm his father.
- 我们以此谎言为生  - 我们以此谎言为生
- The lie we live by. - The lie we live by.
我需要你遵守自己的诺言
I need you to keep your promise.
永远保护他  永远保护我
To always protect him. And me.
我会的
I will.
谢谢观看  更多字幕请关注“幕雨字幕组”新浪微博
你有权掌控任何事  但是不能掌控我  明白吗
You have power over everything but not me, understand?
下集预告
我想要你
I want you.
奥托・鲍威尔虽然是个不错的男人  但同时也很难猜得透
Otto Powell is a good but very complicated man.
你跟我都是同一类人
We're the same, you and me.
你在害怕什么
What are you so frightened of?
- 我才不要进监狱  - 我会处理好的
- I am not going to prison. - I will handle this.
你杀人了吗  查理
Did you kill someone, Charlie?
你再也没有机会扮演上帝的角色了
You are no longer playing God.
- 穆里根到底想要什么  - 我认为他想要我
- What does Mulligan want? - I think he wants me.
还有...毁掉你
And to destroy you.